Finding Aid for the Yuji Ichioka Papers LSC.0242
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Research Materials
  - Immigrant Nationalism
    - Zaigai Doho wo mukaete (1941) (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - Zaigai Doho Daihyosha Kaigi Gijiroku (1941) (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - Kawamota Eiji, "Nihon Kenkoku no Uta," no. 1-3, ca. 1940 (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Newspaper clippings of Senryû ?? and Tanka ?? poems composed by Issei., 1938-1940 (Box 154, Folder 3)
    - Photocopy of Kaigai Dôhô Chûôkai ???????, Kigen Nisenroppyakunen Hôshuku Kaigai Dôhô Tokyo Taikai Hôkokusho ????????????????????? [Report on the Tokyo Convention of Overseas Japanese held in commemoration of the 2600th anniversary of the founding of the nation], 1940 (Box 154, Folder 4)
    - Japanese newspaper articles relating to Kaigai Dôhô Tokyo Taikai???????? ?Tokyo Convention of Overseas Japanese?., November 1940 (Box 154, Folder 5)
    - Kashû Mainichi ???????? clippings relating to Kaigai Dôhô Tokyo Taikai ???????? ?Tokyo Convention of Overseas Japanese, October-November 1940 (Box 154, Folder 6)
    - Shin Sekai ???????? clippings relating to Kaigai Dôhô Tokyo Taikai ???????? ?Tokyo Convention of Overseas Japanese, November 1940 (Box 154, Folder 7)
  - Internment
    - WRA, Impounded People (1946) (Box 92, Folder 1)
    - WRA, The Evacuated People (1946); and Wartime Exile (1946) (Box 92, Folder 2)
    - WRA publications, 3 items (1946) (Box 92, Folder 3)
    - WRA publications, 3 items (1942, 1946) (Box 92, Folder 4)
    - WRA pamphlets (Box 92, Folder 5)
    - Japanese American publications in WRA camps (Box 92, Folder 6)
    - Hashimoto Masaji, Nankin Rokunen, vol. 1 (1954) (Box 92, Folder 7)
    - Hashimoto Masaji, Nankin Rokunen, vol. 2 (1955) (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - Tana Daisho & Tomoe, Santafe Rozubagu Yokuryusho Nikki, vol. 1 (1976) (Box 93, Folder 2)
    - Tana Daisho & Tomoe, Santafe Rozubagu Yokuryusho Nikki, vol. 2 (1978) (Box 93, Folder 3)
    - Papers relating to Frank Emi and draft resisters (Box 93, Folder 4)
    - Papers relating to Joseph Kurihara and Harry Ueno (Box 93, Folder 5)
    - Papers relating to Mike Masaoka and the Japanese American Citizens League during the war (Box 93, Folder 6)
    - JACL wartime publications (Box 94, Folder 1)
    - Minutes of JACL emergency meetings, March 8-9, 1942 (Box 94, Folder 2)
    - Publications and articles relating to Japanese Americans during the war (Box 94, Folder 3)
    - Articles relating to Japanese Americans during the war (Box 94, Folder 4)
    - Studies relating to Japanese American internment, A-F (Box 94, Folder 5)
    - Studies relating to Japanese American internment, H-L (Box 94, Folder 6)
    - Studies relating to Japanese American internment, M-N (Box 94, Folder 7)
    - Studies relating to Japanese American internment, O-Z (Box 94, Folder 8)
  - Issei Miscellanies
    - Nichibei Shimbunsha, Zaibei Nihonjin Nenkan, no. 1 (1905) (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - Clippings of miscellaneous Shin Sekai editorials and articles, 1908-1917 (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Clippings of miscellaneous Shin Sekai editorials and articles, 1918-1924 (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - Clippings of miscellaneous Shin Sekai editorials and articles, 1932 (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - Clippings of miscellaneous Shin Sekai editorials and articles, 1933 (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - Clippings of miscellaneous Shin Sekai editorials and articles, 1934-1935 (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Clippings of miscellaneous Rafu Shimpo editorials, 1917, 1922 (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - Newspaper clippings and consular dispatch relating to factionalism among the Japanese of Seattle (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - Shin Sekai clippings relating to the visits of Ebina Danjo and Kanamori Michinori to California (Box 77, Folder 8)
    - Papers pertaining to Shibusawa Eiichi (Box 77, Folder 9)
    - Nihon Imin Kyokai Hokoku, 1916-1917 (Box 77, Folder 10)
    - Washizu Shakuma, "Rekishi Inmetsu no tan" no. 1-97, Nichibei Shimbun, 1922 (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Transcriptions of Washizu Shakuma, "Rekishi Inmetsu no tan" (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Transcriptions of Washizu Shakuma, "Wagahai no Beikoku Seikatsu," Nichibei Shimbun, 1924-1925 (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Byogen-sei, "28-nenkan no Yoga kaiko," no. 1-100, Shin Sekai, 1931 (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Transcriptions of Byogen-sei, "28-nenkan no Yoga kaiko" (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - Ninomiya Risaku, Omoshiroi Soko (1912) (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - Japanese Medical Society of Los Angeles Minutes (1936-1942) (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - Copies of Soko Jiji (1895-1896); Shin Sekai (1896); and Nichibei Shimbun (1905) (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - Japanese foreign ministry reports on Japanese communities in the Pacific Northwest printed in TsûshÔ isan ??????., 1908-1909 (Box 154, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous immigrant newspaper articles., Undated. (Box 154, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous immigrant statistics., Undated. (Box 154, Folder 15)
  - Japanese Associations
    - Beikoku Soko Dai-Nihonjinkai, 1897-1900 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Zaibei Nihonjin Kyogikai, 1900 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Zaibei Nihonjin Kyogikai, 1900-1903 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Zaibei Nihonjin Rengo Kyogikai, Hokokusho (1907) (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Zaibei Nihonjinkai, Hokokusho (1909-1918) (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Zaibei Nihonjinkai, Meishi Shotai Hokoku (1912) with clippings (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Newspaper clippings pertaining to the Japanese Association of America, 1908 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Newspaper clippings pertaining to the Japanese Association of America, 1909 (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Newspaper clippings pertaining to the Japanese Association of America, 1910 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper clippings pertaining to the Japanese Association of America, 1911 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Newspaper clippings pertaining to the Japanese Association of America, 1912 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper clippings pertaining to the Japanese Association of America, 1913 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Newspaper clippings pertaining to the Japanese Association of America, 1914 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Newspaper clippings pertaining to the Japanese Association of America, 1915 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Newspaper clippings pertaining to the Japanese Association of America, 1916 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Newspaper clippings pertaining to the Japanese Association of America, 1917 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper clippings pertaining to the Japanese Association of America, 1918 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Newspaper clippings pertaining to the Japanese Association of America, 1919 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper clippings pertaining to the Japanese Association of America, 1920 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Newspaper clippings pertaining to the Japanese Association of America, 1921 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Newspaper clippings pertaining to the Japanese Association of America, 1922 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Newspaper clippings pertaining to the Japanese Association of America, 1922 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Newspaper clippings pertaining to the Japanese Association of America, 1923 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper clippings pertaining to the Japanese Association of America, 1924- 1925 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Newspaper clippings pertaining to the Japanese Association of America, 1926- 1931 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper clippings pertaining to the Japanese Association of San Francisco, 1917- 1918 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Newspaper clippings pertaining to disputes within the Japanese Association of San Francisco, 1920 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Newspaper clippings pertaining to disputes within the Japanese Association of San Francisco, 1920-21 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Newspaper clippings pertaining to the split of the Fresno Japanese Association, 1912- 1914 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Newspaper clippings pertaining to local Japanese Association affiliates, 1913- 1916 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Newspaper clippings pertaining to local Japanese Association affiliates, 1919-1920, 1922 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Minutes of Japanese Association affiliates in Walnut Grove and Stockton (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Nanka Chuo Nihonjinkai, 1924 Annual Report (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Beikoku Seihokubu Renraku Nihonjinkai, Report, August 20, 1920-February 28, 1921 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Beikoku Seihokubu Renraku Nihonjinkai, Report, March 1, 1921-August 31, 1921 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Beikoku Seihokubu Renraku Nihonjinkai, Reports, September 1, 1921-July 31, 1922 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Beikoku Seihokubu Renraku Nihonjinkai, Report, March 1, 1923-February 29, 1924 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Newspaper clippings pertaining to Taiheiyo Engan Nihonjinkai Kyogikai, 1914- 1924 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Research notes from the minutes of Taiheiyo Engan Nihonjinkai Kyogikai, 1914- 1928 (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Papers pertaining to Taiheiyo Engan Nihonjinkai Kyogikai's 1917 resolution (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Japanese Foreign Ministry
    - Gaimusho, Nihon Gaiko Bunsho, 1891-1896 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Gaimusho, Nihon Gaiko Bunsho, 1897-1900 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Gaimusho, Nihon Gaiko Bunsho, 1901-1904 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Gaimusho, Nihon Gaiko Bunsho, 1905-1909 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Gaimusho Tsushokyoku, "Imin Toriatsukai-nin ni yoru Imin no enkaku," 1909 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Japanese diplomatic papers relating to emigration restrictions and Issei petitions (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Japanese diplomatic papers relating to Issei-owned banks in San Francisco (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Japanese diplomatic papers relating to Issei-owned bank in Sacramento (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Hanihara Masanao, Report, November 1908 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Morita Kojiro, Report, January 20, 1909 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Numano Yasutaro, Report, May 1909 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Oyama Ujiro, Report, October 1909 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Zai Soko Nihon Ryojikan, Report, 1909 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Consular reports on the effects of immigration restrictions, 1911 (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Consular reports on the living conditions of Japanese in Oregon, Idaho, and Washington, 1922-1923 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - Consular reports on the living conditions of Japanese in Nevada, Utah, and Colorado, November 1926 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - Foreign Ministry dispatches relating to the abolition of certificate rights, 1924- 1925 (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Foreign Ministry reports, 2 items, 1936, 1938 (Box 53, Folder 10)
  - Japanese Wartime Propaganda
    - Radio Tokyo research project grant proposals (Box 100, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence & interviews relating to Radio Tokyo research project (Box 100, Folder 2)
    - Kitayama Setsuro articles relating to Radio Tokyo propaganda (Box 100, Folder 3)
    - Indexes for December 1941 file of "Memovox Records and "Sound Recordings" (Box 100, Folder 4)
    - Selected transcripts of Radio Tokyo shortwave broadcast, 1942 (Box 100, Folder 5)
    - Selected transcripts of Radio Tokyo shortwave broadcast, 1942 (Box 100, Folder 6)
    - Selected transcripts of Radio Tokyo shortwave broadcast, 1942 (Box 100, Folder 7)
    - Radio Tokyo transcripts, December 8-20, 1941 (Box 100, Folder 8)
    - Radio Tokyo transcripts, December 21-31, 1941 (Box 101, Folder 1)
    - Radio Tokyo transcripts, January 2-15, 1942 (Box 101, Folder 2)
    - Radio Tokyo transcripts, January 23-31, 1942 (Box 101, Folder 3)
    - Radio Tokyo transcripts, February 1-12, 1942 (Box 101, Folder 4)
    - Radio Tokyo transcripts, February 13-28, 1942 (Box 101, Folder 5)
    - Radio Tokyo transcripts, March 1-15, 1942 (Box 101, Folder 6)
    - Radio Tokyo transcripts, March 16-31, 1942 (Box 102, Folder 1)
    - Radio Tokyo transcripts, April 1-14, 1942 (Box 102, Folder 2)
    - Radio Tokyo transcripts, April 16-30, 1942 (Box 102, Folder 3)
    - Radio Tokyo transcripts, May 1-14, 1942 (Box 102, Folder 4)
    - Radio Tokyo transcripts, May 16-31, 1942 (Box 102, Folder 5)
    - Radio Tokyo transcripts, June 1942 (Box 102, Folder 6)
    - Radio Tokyo transcripts, July 1-August 9, 1942 (Box 103, Folder 1)
    - Radio Tokyo transcripts, August 10-31, 1942 (Box 103, Folder 2)
    - Radio Tokyo transcripts, September 1-20, 1942 (Box 103, Folder 3)
    - Radio Tokyo transcripts, September 21-October 30, 1942 (Box 103, Folder 4)
    - Radio Tokyo transcripts, November 1-December 6, 1942 (Box 103, Folder 5)
    - Radio Tokyo transcripts, December 7-14, 1942 (Box 103, Folder 6)
    - Radio Tokyo transcripts, December 15-31, 1942 (Box 103, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous Radio Tokyo transcripts (Box 103, Folder 8)
    - Japan Times & Advertizer editorial clippings, 1942 (Box 104, Folder 1)
    - Nippon Times editorial clippings, 1943 (Box 104, Folder 2)
    - Nippon Times editorial clippings, 1944 (Box 104, Folder 3)
    - Dai-Niji Kokansen Teia maru no Hokoku (1944); and Amerika Kankin Seikatsu (1943) (Box 104, Folder 4)
    - Amerika Seikanki (1942); and Tekikoku Amerika (1942) (Box 104, Folder 5)
    - Sokoku ni kaeru (1943); and Senjika Amerika ni Kokyusuru (1942) (Box 104, Folder 6)
  - Kawakami Kiyoshi
    - FBI file, mostly 1921-1922 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - FBI file, 1920-1924, 1941-1945, 1950 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - FBI file, 1939-1945 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - FBI file, 1939-1941 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - FBI file, 1940-1945 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - ONI file, 1921-1923 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - ONI file, 1921-1925 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Department of State file, 1920-1923, 1936, 1938-1941 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Department of State and Army files, 1921, 1941-1942 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Department of Justice, "Report of the Attorney General..." (June 1945), pp. 1- 249 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Department of Justice, "Report of the Attorney General..." (June 1945), pp. 251- 560 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous writings by Kawakami, and his letters to Chester Rowell, 1914- 1920 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - K. K. Kawakami, Japan in World Politics (1917); and The Real Japanese Question (1921) (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - K. K. Kawakami, Japan Speaks on the Sino-Japanese Crisis (1932); and Manchukuo (1933) (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Kenjinkai
    - Nanpo, vol. 1-3 (1925-1927) (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - Zaibei Okinawa Kenjinkai Kaiho (January 1935); Kenjin no Tomo Kaiho (June 1935) (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - Ryukyu, no. 3-4 (1936-1937) (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - Ryukyu, no. 5-6 (1938-1939) (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - Ryukyu, no. 7 (1940) (Box 70, Folder 8)
    - Okayama Kaigai Kyokai Shiatoru shibu Hattenshi (1930) (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Endo Shiro, Minami Kashu Okayama Kenjin Hattenshi (1941) (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - Hayato, 1908-1916 (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - Kuno Yoshisaburo
    - Biographical information, clippings, and correspondencce, 1914-1919 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1920-1931 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Mori Shingen, Kunosan Seianji Bochi yori (1969) (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Labor Migration and Labor Contractors
    - Materials relating to contract laborers in Hawaii (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Takahashi Kanji, Imin no Chichi (1953) (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Tanaka Chushichi's report on Japanese raildroad workers, September 1892 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Seattle consul's report on Issei labor contractors and new immigrant workers, 1897- 1898 (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Consular reports on the use of false passports by labor immigrants, 1900 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Clippings of Shizuoka Min`yu Shimbun relating to Yamaoka Ototaka, December 1900- June 1901 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Materials pertaining to Ban Shinzaburo and Yamaoka Ototaka (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - Newspaper clippings and research notes relating to Issei labor contractors, 1899- 1917 (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - Labor contractors' advertisements (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - Papers relating to the remigration of Japanese workers from Hawaii to the mainland U.S., 1902-1904 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Papers relating to the remigration of Japanese workers from Hawaii to the mainland U.S., 1905-1907 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence relating to the hiring of Japanese workers by the Northern Pacific Railway, 1902-1904 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence relating to the hiring of Japanese workers by the Northern Pacific Railway, 1905-1906 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence relating to the hiring of Japanese workers by the Northern Pacific Railway, 1907-1908 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous papers pertaining to labor conditions and contracting business (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Labor Migration and Labor Contractors
    - Documents from the Great Northern and Northern Pacific Railway Archives., 1903-1918 (Box 155, Folder 5)
      (See also Box 55, Folders 3-5.)
    - Selected photocopies of the Reports of State Mine Inspector. Wyoming., 1889-1906 (Box 155, Folder 6)
    - Selected photocopies of the Reports of State Mine Inspector. Wyoming., 1907-1910 (Box 155, Folder 7)
  - Labor Organizing
    - Research notes on Suzuki Bunji (Box 61, Folder 11)
    - Suzuki Bunji's writings, 1915-1917 (Box 61, Folder 12)
    - English-language materials relating to Suzuki Bunji and his visit to America (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Studies of Suzuki Bunji and Yuaikai (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Shin Sekai clippings relating to labor organizing and Suzuki's visit to America, 1915- 1917 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous materials relating to Suzuki Bunji and Yuaikai (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - United Mine Workers' Journal editorial and commentaries on Asian immigrant labor, 1901-1902 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - American Federationist and International Socialist Review editorials on Asian labor, 1901-1910 (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - Japanese consular reports on the United Mine Workers of Ameirca, 1907 (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - Wyoming and Colorado newspaper clippings and notes (Box 62, Folder 8)
    - Colorado Shimbun clippings relating to the 1913 coal mine strike and "Ludlaw Massacre," 1913-1914 (Box 62, Folder 9)
    - Research notes and statistical data relating to coal mine workers and strikes (Box 62, Folder 10)
    - Research notes pertaining to Issei coal mine workers and labor contractors (Box 62, Folder 11)
    - Annual Report of Wyoming State Coal Mine Inspector, 1915-1921 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Erma A. Fletcher, "A History of the Labor Movement in Wyoming, 1870-1940" (1945) (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Nisei and Louis Adamic
    - Louis Adamic correspondence with Nisei, 1939-1942 (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - Charles Kikuchi life story, and his correspondence with Adamic, 1939-1945 (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - Nisei writings on Adamic and his publications, 1939-1943 (Box 88, Folder 3)
    - Larry Tajiri's Common Ground articles, and his correspondence with Editor, 1943- 1947 (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - Eddie Shima and Jade Snow Wong articles in Common Ground, and their correspondence, 1942-1950 (Box 88, Folder 5)
    - Bradford Smith's Common Ground articles on Nisei, and his correspondence, 1942, 1946-1949 (Box 88, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous Common Ground articles, 1940-1949 (Box 88, Folder 7)
    - Research notes and miscellanies (Box 88, Folder 8)
    - Papers presented at Louis Adamic international symposiums, 1981 (Box 88, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous writings relating to Adamic (Box 88, Folder 10)
  - Nisei Individual Files
    - Saburo Kido, "Timely Topics," Shin Sekai, January-August 1937 (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Saburo Kido, "Timely Topics," Shin Sekai, September 1937-March 1938 (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Saburo Kido, "Timely Topics," Shin Sekai, April-December 1938 (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - Tamotsu Murayama FBI file (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Tamotsu Murayama's prewar writings, 1935-1938 (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Tamotsu Murayama's Japanese magazine articles, 1942-1950 (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - Tamotsu Murayama correspondence, ca. 1932-1937, 1950s (Box 79, Folder 7)
    - Pacific Citizen articles by Tamotsu Murayama, 1953-1971 (Box 79, Folder 8)
    - Murayama Tamotsu, Shigosen Nanboku (1936) (Box 79, Folder 9)
    - Jimmy Omura prewar writings (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Jimmy Omura's Rocky Shimpo editorials, 1944, 1947 (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Jimmy Omura's miscellaneous writings, 1940-1980s (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - James Sakamoto's editorials and columns in Japanese American Courier, 1928- 1932 (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - James Sakamoto's editorials and columns in Japanese American Courier, 1934- 1942 (Box 80, Folder 5)
    - Clippings of James Sakamoto's miscellaneous articles in Japanese American Courier, 1934-1942 (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - James Sakamoto correspondence, 1930-1944, 1953, 1955 (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - James Sakamoto FBI file (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - Clippings relating to the death of James Sakamoto, 1955 (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Research notes on James Sakamoto (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - Mayumi Tsutakawa, "The Political Conservatism of James Sakamoto's Japanese American Courier" (1976) (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - Materials pertaining to the family of Buddy Kazumaro Uno (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - Howard Uno, "Trials and Tribulations of George Kumemaro Uno" (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - Uno family genealogy and its Japanese family registry (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - Buddy Uno's biographical materials, family interviews, and research notes (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - Buddy Uno's prewar English writings, Rafu Shimpo, 1931-1935 (Box 81, Folder 8)
    - Buddy Uno's prewar English writings, Rafu Shimpo and Shin Sekai, 1934, 1936- 1937 (Box 81, Folder 9)
    - Buddy Uno's prewar English writings, Rafu Shimpo and Nichibei Shimbun, 1938- 1940 (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - Buddy Uno's prewar English writings, Shin Sekai and other community newspapers, 1937-1941 (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - Buddy Uno's wartime writings (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - Yuji Ichioka research correspondence relating to Buddy Uno, 1994-1998 (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous research notes on Buddy Uno (Box 82, Folder 5)
    - Carl Mydans, More Than Meets the Eyes (1959), and his other writings relating to Uno (Box 82, Folder 6)
    - Buddy Uno war crime investigation file (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - Buddy Uno war crime investigation file (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - Buddy Uno war crime investigation file (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - U.S. government investigative reports on George Kumemaro Uno (Uno Kumemaro) (Box 83, Folder 4)
    - FBI file on George Kumemaro Uno (Uno Kumemaro) (Box 83, Folder 5)
    - Iva Toguri FBI file and court papers (Box 83, Folder 6)
    - Freedom (1942) (Box 83, Folder 7)
    - Bill Hosokawa and Larry Tajiri newspaper articles, 1930s-1950s (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - John T. Fujii's writings (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - Kazuo Kawai's biographical materials, newspaper writings, and correspondence, 1925- 1938 (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - Dyke Miyagawa and Nisei labor activism, 1930s (Box 84, Folder 4)
    - Miya Sannomiya and Henry Toshiro Shimanouchi materials, 1930s (Box 84, Folder 5)
    - Louise Suski's "Biography," and her reports on Nisei in Chicago and Milwaukee, October-December 1943 (Box 84, Folder 6)
    - Louise Suski's reports on Nisei in Chicago and Milwaukee, 1944-April 1945 (Box 84, Folder 7)
    - Hisaye Yamamoto (Napoleon) and Toyo Suyemoto newspaper articles, 1937-1941, 1985, 1993 (Box 84, Folder 8)
    - Togo Tanaka, "History of J.A.C.L," ca. 1942 (Box 84, Folder 9)
    - Togo Tanaka, "The Vernacular Newspaper," ca. 1942 (Box 84, Folder 10)
  - Nisei Miscellanies
    - Shin Sekai English clippings relating to Nisei, 1937-1938 (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Rafu Shimpo English and Japanese clippings relating to Nisei, 1929-1941 (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - Japanese newspaper clippings relating to Nisei and the Sino-Japanese conflict, 1937- 1941 (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - English periodical articles relating to Nisei (Box 89, Folder 4)
    - Richard Kenmotsu's newspaper clippings file relating to Nisei in Japan (Box 89, Folder 5)
    - Richard Kenmotsu's newspaper clippings file relating to Nisei in Japan, etc. (Box 89, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous Issei publications on Nisei, 1930s (Box 89, Folder 7)
  - Other Issei Individuals
    - Dodo Masao materials (Box 42, Folder 4)